# Mohammad Jahanseir

406, 640 Main Street, Saskatoon, SK S7H 0J7 (306) 716-5524 | mjahanseir@gmail.com Permanent Resident (PR)

I am an experienced IT professional, with a master's degree certified by WES in Computer Engineering and over 14 years of IT experience. I am currently taking a Full Stack Java Course with ComIT in Saskatoon to update my abilities and hope to start a career as a software developer because I find it to be a satisfying and demanding job in the high-tech industry.

## **Areas of Expertise**

- Programming: Java, Java Script, HTML, CSS
- Database: My SQL, SQL Server
- Operating System: Windows (Clients and Servers), Linux (Ubuntu and other GUI versions)
- Network: Cisco
- Multi Media: Adobe Photoshop and Premiere

#### **Academic Education**

Computer Engineering - Software (Master's Degree) Islamic Azad University (IAU), Iran	2013
Computer Engineering - Software (Bachelor's Degree) Islamic Azad University (IAU), Iran	2009
Applied Computer - Software (Associate's Degree) Islamic Azad University (IAU), Iran	2004
* WES Credential Evaluation (ICAP) report available	2019
Technical Education	
Full Stack Java Developer ComIT, Canada	2019
MCITP 2008 Server Administrator Kahkeshan Noor Institute of Technology, Iran	2011
Network+ (CompTIA Network+) Kahkeshan Noor Institute of Technology, Iran	2010
Information Technology (IT) in Multi Media (Level 1)	2003
Tehran Technical and Vocational Training Organization, Iran Information Technology (IT) in Multi Media (Level 2) Tehran Technical and Vocational Training Organization, Iran	2003
Hardware Technician (CompTIA A+) Tehran Technical and Vocational Training Organization, Iran	2003

## **Work Experience**

# SEO and Social media Expert(Casual)

1Maids

• Relevant Duties: web site and social media optimization

# Web Site Design (Casual) (www.drmazhari.com)

• Relevant Duties: Website designing and maintaining with CMS

Apr. 2013 - Present

Apr. 2019 - Present

### IT Expert - Subcontracted with CP (Canadian Pacific)

Atlas Office Solution, Saskatoon, Canada

 Relevant Duties: Network and wireless systems setup, workgroup and domain setup, desktop and mobile printer setup, website design and maintenance, SMB, SMTP, FTP configuration and troubleshooting all hardware and network issues Dec. 2018 - Apr. 2019

### **Computer Expert**

Islamic Azad University (IAU), Science and Research Branch, Tehran, Iran

• *Relevant Duties:* Installing and configuring computer hardware, software, networks, printers and scanners. Monitoring, maintaining and troubleshooting computer systems and networks, website managing, conference setup and collaborating with other departments for a university population of 45,000 students and 3000 faculty members.

May 2004 – Jul. 2018

#### **University Lecturer**

• University of Applied Science and Technology, Tehran, Iran

• Islamic Azad University (IAU), Damavand Branch, Iran

• SAMA Technical and Vocational Center, Damavand, Iran

• Islamic Azad University (IAU), Hashtgerd Branch, Iran

Feb. 2015 – Feb. 2018 Sep. 2013 – Jul. 2015 Feb. 2014 – Jul. 2015 Sep. 2012 – Feb. 2013

• *Some Courses Taught*: Programming Languages (C++, Visual Basic, and Web), Operating Systems, Databases, Computer Networks, LAN Design, Network Management, TCP / IP Protocols, Switches and Routers, etc.

Network Expert Apr. 2004 – Sep. 2005

Alborz Computer Company (Internet Service Provider), Tehran, Iran

• *Relevant Duties:* Network monitoring, troubleshooting and solving users' problems for one of the biggest internet service providers at the time.

#### References

#### Farid Ahmadzadeh

Manager of Atlas Office Solution #1101 Scarth Street, Regina, SK, S4R 2E3 (306)591-3466, Fax (306)5453466 info@atlasoffice.ca

#### Maryam Akhgar

Manager of 1 Maids #1614 Briarwood Rd, Saskatoon, SK S7V 1H2 (306)341-0725 care@1maids.com

#### **Elwood Stewart**

English Teacher in Saskatoon Global Gathering Place #1908 Haultain Ave, Saskatoon, SK, S7J 1P3 (306)652-1563 abbers@sasktel.net

Linkedin.com/in/jahanseir Github.com/mjahanseir

Mohammad Jahanseir (306) 716-5524 Page 2